Guide to the Stanford University Facilities and Grounds Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University facilities and grounds collection
1956-2009
SC0970
Stanford University. Land, Buildings and Real Estate.
1.25 Linear feet
The collection, assembled by Herb Fong, manager in Grounds Services, includes reports, operations manuals, memoranda, and other materials pertaining largely to campus trees and plants and their care.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
The collection, assembled by Herb Fong, manager in Grounds Services, includes reports, operations manuals, memoranda, and other materials pertaining largely to campus trees and plants and their care.
Access Terms
Fong, Herb.; Landscape gardening --California --Stanford.; Trees--California--Stanford.
Collection Contents
- Reports, manuals, and other records, 1956-12009; Accession 2009-062; 1.25 Linear feet
  - AFM [Administrative and Financial Management] Report for Grounds Department, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dutch Elm Disease project, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Engineering Associates, Report on Study of Grounds Operation, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engineering Associates, Grounds Operations for Stanford University, 1996 Sep (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Engineering Associates, Grounds Operations for Stanford University, 1996 Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eucalyptus trees (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Evaluation of Peninsula Sanitary Service Recycling Programs and Front-Loader Bin Service, Prepared by Brown, Vence & Associates, 1995 Feb (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Frost Amphitheater plants, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Grounds Services Operations Sections 1-9, [Overview; Supervisors and Crews; Grounds Maintenance Areas; Inventory Summary; Plant Inventory; Irrigation Inventory; Tree Inventory; Targets; Work Budget], 2009- March (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Grounds Services Operations Sections 10-16 [Outage Class Reports; Cost Estimates; Equipment Operators Crew; Road Maintenance Crew; Grounds Perimeter Crew; Specialty Housing Crew; Cleanup/Weeding Crew], 2009 March (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Grounds Services Operations Sections 17-18, [Shrub & Groundcover Trim Crew; Horticulturists], 2009 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grounds Services Operations Sections 19-23, [Pest Control Crew; Tree Crew; Construction Crew; Irrigation Crew; Appendix], 2009 March (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Harris, Richard, “A Management Approach to Park Maintenance,” with note by Herb Fong, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Landscape Maintenance Guidelines, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Los Trancos San Francisquito Creeks Monitor reports, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Milestone Memos [gathered by Herb Fong], 1981-2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Oaks, information re compiled by David Muffly, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Presentation on work standards, 1983-1984 and undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Recycling Options for Stanford University, Prepared by Brown, Vence & Associates, 1987 Sep (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SLAC Memorial Trees (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Solid Waste Generation Study, Prepared by Brown, Vence & Associates, 1991 Dec (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Solid Waste Management Plan, Prepared by Brown, Vence & Associates, 1987 Sep (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tree information (includes heritage tree list 1977, list of Inner Quad trees and shrubs 1955, Tree Walk handout 1973) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Trees of Stanford, Campus Report, 1984 Nov 14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - WOFAC, work management program, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - WOFAC, work management, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - WOFAC materials, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SUMC. A Management Review of the Facilities Department, 1979 March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Syllabus for Biology 131 Mosses and Ferns, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bracewell, Ron. Trees on the Stanford Campus, 1973 May (Box 3, Folder 4)